ctsummation.com 2010-12-15

# AccessData Group - Privacy Policy

This site is owned and operated by AccessData Group LLC company. Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. We want to make your experience online satisfying and safe.

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it.

We gather two types of information about users:

  1. Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions to receive our electronic newsletters, to participate in our message boards or forums, to email a friend, and from participation in polls and surveys. 
  2. Information gathered through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers’ needs and to help our advertisers and sponsors better understand the demographics of our audience. Because this site derives its revenue mainly from sponsorships and advertising, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential to keeping our service free to users. 

We offer a free electronic newsletter to users that choose to subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. Users can also subscribe to the newsletters at the time of registration.

Users of the site’s Discussion Boards must register (free of charge) in order to post messages. During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address.

Our site users can choose to electronically forward a link, page, or documents to someone else by clicking “e-mail this to a friend”. The user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used only in the case of transmission errors and, or course, to let the recipient know who sent the email. The information is not used for any other purpose.

We may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what our audience thinks about important issues. Opinions or other responses to polls are aggregated and are not identifiable to any particular user. The site may use a system to “tag” users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users.

The site may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our sponsors, advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party.

Consistent with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPRA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent.

The sites tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. The site does break down overall usage statistics according to a user’s domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user’s browser).  
The site sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don’t like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you.

We may place a text file called a “cookie” in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can’t read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. The cookies are used to track user traffic patterns (as described above).

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you’ve set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you may need cookies to participate actively in message boards, forums, polling and surveys.

The site uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interest of our users.  
As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, and forums. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing.

When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don’t like based on traffic to those areas, we do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps use continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don’t track which terms a particular user enters.

We take reasonable steps to protect your personally identifiable information as you transmit your information from your computer to our site and to protect such information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. You should keep in mind that no Internet transmission is ever 100% secure or error-free. In particular, email sent to or from this site may not be secure, and you should therefore take special care in deciding what information you send to us. Moreover, where you use passwords, ID numbers, or other special access features on this site, it is your responsibility to safeguard them.

This site may contain links or references to other web sites. Please be aware that we do not control those web sites and that, in any case, this Privacy Policy does not apply to those web sites. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of every web site you visit.

We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include:  
* Opting not to register to receive our electronic newsletters   
* Opting not to be contacted by telephone, direct mail or email   
* Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely alleviates the need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users. 

**Consent**

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

 >> Top
